MENUMENU

*  

Privacy Policy
==============

[Home](https://www.educba.com/) **Privacy Policy**

**Last Updated – 7th June, 2020**

If you have questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or if you wish to update, correct or delete any information you have provided to us, please contact EDUCBA at [Contact Us](https://www.educba.com/contact-us/)

Privacy Policy – EDUCBA
-----------------------

EDUCBA is committed to protecting any personal information you provide in connection with your use of this website, (the “Site”). This Privacy Policy describes what information we collect when you visit the Site, how we collect it, how we use it and the steps we take to protect it. We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time and when we do, we will post the modified policy. We may also provide additional notice for more significant changes to the Privacy Policy. By submitting information to us or continuing to use the Site after we have posted any modifications, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, which are incorporated into and a part of our Terms.

### Purchasing E-Learning Materials

If you wish to purchase any E-Learning Materials, you will automatically be redirected to the EDUCBA registration page. EDUCBA will collect and use your personal information in accordance with the privacy policy posted in the Site. We encourage all visitors who wish to purchase E-Learning Materials from EDUCBA to read our privacy policy so that you will know how your personal information will be collected, used, and shared.

### Information Gathered Through The Site

EDUCBA may track and record certain non-personal information of website users, including IP address, operating system, type of browser, referring URL, and time spent on the Site in order to gain aggregate data that may be analyzed for trends and statistics on how our visitors use the Site. EDUCBA may use accumulated aggregate non-personal data for several purposes including, but not limited to, Site traffic analysis, evaluation of EDUCBA’s services, and program planning. EDUCBA may also market anonymous, non-identifiable user data that has been collected and processed into aggregate and anonymous statistical profiles to third parties. EDUCBA may use a third-party website analytics provider to track and record non-personal information of the website users and provide reports based on such information to EDUCBA. Such providers may use that non-personal information for their internal purposes.

EDUCBA will only collect personal information of users (i.e. name, postal address, email address, credit card number, telephone number), if those users wish to contact us, register for courses, or receive notification of new products or upcoming courses. EDUCBA does not store credit/debit card numbers of the users in its server as those are processed only by the respective payment gateway chosen by the user during the  checkout. EDUCBA will only use your personal information (name, email, telephone number) for the purposes for which you provide it. If, after registering for any such notifications, you no longer wish to be contacted regarding EDUCBA services or activities that we think may be of interest to you, you may let us know at any time by sending an email to [\[email protected\]](https://www.educba.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or contacting us as described below.  We may also share your personal information (name, email, telephone number) with third parties who provide services to us in connection with the website or disclose it in special circumstances if we have a good-faith belief that it is necessary to enforce this Privacy Policy, protect the safety of anyone or that such disclosure is required by law.

We use Stripe, Paypal, Razorpay, and 2Checkout for payment, analytics, and other business services. You can learn more about their privacy policies below –

* Stripe privacy policy at https://stripe.com/privacy
* Paypal Privacy Policy – https://www.paypal.com/en/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full
* 2Checkout – https://www.2checkout.com/legal/privacy/
* Razorpay – https://razorpay.com/privacy/

### Links

The Site contains links to other websites that are owned or controlled by third parties. Please note that the privacy policies of these sites may differ from those of the Site. EDUCBA is not responsible for the privacy policies and practices of any linked website. We encourage you to read the privacy policy of any website you wish to visit before disclosing any information.

### Other Notification

In order to implement or enforce this Privacy Policy or other Terms or to notify users EDUCBA may use information you have provided to contact you.

### Enforcement

If EDUCBA becomes aware that the security of the website is compromised or any nonpublic user information has been disclosed to unrelated third parties as a result of external activity or otherwise not in accordance with this Privacy Policy, EDUCBA will take reasonable measures that it deems appropriate (which may include an internal investigation and reporting, notifying the user, and notifying and cooperating with law enforcement authorities)

### Security

We will use reasonable efforts to safeguard any personal information that you provide through the website. Nevertheless, no transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.

### Service Providers

Our service providers may not be located in your geographic area. By providing your personal information on the website, you also consent to the transfer of your data to these service providers.

### Contact Us

If you have questions or concerns about these Terms or the Site or if you wish to update, correct or delete any information you have provided to us, please contact EDUCBA at [\[email protected\]](https://www.educba.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

### Cookie Policy

**What is a cookie and what does it do?**  
Cookies are small text files stored by your browser as you browse the internet. They can be used to collect, store, and share data about your activities across websites, including on EDUCBA. Cookies also allow us to remember things about your visits to EDUCBA, like your preferred language, and to make the site easier to use.

We use both session cookies, which expire after a short time or when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which remain stored in your browser for a set period of time. We use session cookies to identify you during a single browsing session, like when you log into EDUCBA.

**Why does EDUCBA use cookies?**  
We use cookies and similar technologies like local shared objects, to deliver, measure, and improve our services in various ways. We use these cookies both when you visit our site and services through a browser and through our mobile app. As we adopt additional technologies, we may also gather additional data through other methods. We also use third party cookies to help deliver relevant courses and advertising both on EDUCBA and on other websites, to integrate content with social networks, such as Facebook, Google+, twitter, and to better understand how the features and functions of the site are used in order that we can improve our service.

We use cookies for the following purposes:

**User Access :**

1. To log you into EDUCBA
2. To protect your security
3. To help detect and fight spam, abuse, and other activities that violate EDUCBA’s agreements

For example, cookies help authenticate your access to EDUCBA and prevent unauthorized parties from accessing your accounts.

**Preferences**

1. To store previously access data
2. To save your settings and other choices you’ve made

**Analytics and research**  
To help us improve and understand how people use EDUCBA. For example, cookies help us test different versions of EDUCBA to see which features or content users prefer, web beacons help us determine which email messages are opened, and cookies help us see how you interact with EDUCBA, like the links you click on.

We also work with a number of analytics partners, including Google Analytics, and Comm100, who use cookies and similar technologies to help us analyze how users use the Services, including by noting the sites from which you arrive. Those service providers may either collect that data themselves or we may disclose it to them.

Footer
------

###### Follow us!

###### APPS

###### Company

###### Work with us

###### EDUCBA for Enterprise

###### Resources

###### Popular Categories

ISO 10004:2018 & ISO 9001:2015 Certified

© 2024 - EDUCBA. ALL RIGHTS RESERVED. THE CERTIFICATION NAMES ARE THE TRADEMARKS OF THEIR RESPECTIVE OWNERS.

X

Let’s Get Started

Email ID \*   

By signing up, you agree to our [Terms of Use](https://www.educba.com/terms-and-conditions/) and [Privacy Policy](https://www.educba.com/privacy-policy/).

X

Let’s Get Started

Email ID \*   

By signing up, you agree to our [Terms of Use](https://www.educba.com/terms-and-conditions/) and [Privacy Policy](https://www.educba.com/privacy-policy/).

X

x

_\*Please provide your correct email id. Login details for this Free course will be emailed to you_

X

X

EDUCBA Login

Username

Password

Submit

X

This website or its third-party tools use cookies, which are necessary to its functioning and required to achieve the purposes illustrated in the cookie policy. By closing this banner, scrolling this page, clicking a link or continuing to browse otherwise, you agree to our [Privacy Policy](https://www.educba.com/privacy-policy/?source=popup "Privacy Policy")

OK
